I, Asseylum Vers Allusia,
私　アセイラム・ヴァース・アリューシアは
accept Count Slaine Saazbaum Troyard into my family as my husband,
スレイン・ザーツバルム・トロイヤード伯爵を夫に迎え
and hereby announce that our new kingdom shall be here on Earth.
この地球圏に新たな王国を築くことを宣言します
Presently, despite the valiant service of my proud knights,
今　勇猛果敢なる皆さんの奮戦にもかかわらず
it seems that this war will be a protracted one.
この戦いは　長引く様相を見せています
In which case, what should our course of action be?
事ここに至って私たちは　何を成すべきなのでしょう
Is this the time for infighting?
軌道騎士同士で相争う時でしょうか
Is this the time for service with only glory in mind?
我先に功を競う時でしょうか
Now is the time to assemble under one flag
一つの旗印の元に集い
and fight together for the future of Vers.
ヴァースの未来のため　ともに戦う時が来たのです
I have delegated all my authority to my soon-to-be husband, Count Troyard,
私は　私の持つ権限の一切を
新たに力を与えた城の城主であり
who is also the lord of this reclaimed castle.
やがて私の伴侶となる　トロイヤード伯爵に委ねました
This includes bestowing the power to wake Aldnoah upon others.
アルドノアを呼び覚ます力を誰に与えるか その采配も含めたすべてを
Until the day when we achieve victory in this war,
この戦いに勝利が訪れるその日まで
I implore you to regard his voice as mine
トロイヤード伯爵の言葉を 私の言葉と思い
彼の元に集うことを　心より願います
and rally under his banner.
For the future of Vers.
すべては　ヴァースのために
kimi no te ga hirogeta nani mo nai sora yo
Your hands spread out the vast and empty sky
君の手が広げた　何もない空よ
rikutsu no umi dake no kai wo asobeba
when you played with what the sea of reason would give
理屈の海だけの　解を遊べば
hodoite wa koboreta tagai no namida
Our tears welled up and fell
ほどいては溢れた　お互いのナミダ
kouka shita kotoba uso kimagure
Words, lies, and whim down from orbit
降下した言葉・嘘・キマグレ
soul art
Soul art
soul・art　リズムを奏でて
rhythm kanadete
We play a song now
aizu wo ringu ni tsunagu
and connect the signs to a ring
合図をリングに繋ぐ
形だけのシステムと
katachi dake no system to
A system of pure shape
katami dake no majinai mo
A magic spell without power
形見だけの呪いも
toubounin no hajirai on
The sound of shy fugitives
逃亡人の恥じらい音
想像Drive　CarryOn　意地なTIRE
souzou drive carryon iji na tire
Carry on imagining, don't give up
誤解あるドアに　ゼロが眠りかけた
gokai aru doa ni zero ga nemurikaketa
We're running out of false doors
tokei daita hito to tenshi
Men and angels embrace the passage of time
時計抱いた人と天使
towa ni aku doorutachi
They are dolls who gave up on eternity,
永久に飽くドール達
mata onaji kaze ni mogaite
fighting against this recurring fever
また同じ風邪に　モガいて
相変わらず地球への攻撃は　苦戦続きのようだが
The war against Earth proves as difficult as it always has.
Yes.
はい
That said, Her Highness' words were surely messianic for our deeply unsettled knights.
ただ　この状況に不安を感じる騎士たちにとって
姫殿下の宣言は　天啓のごとく聞こえたのではないでしょうか
Messianic?
天啓？
Nobody doubts that you are the ultimate originator of that proclamation.
あの宣言は　スレイン様の存在あるが故に発せられたものと
誰もが承知しています
The knights that are unsure about our ability to continue this war seek someone to lead them.
現状に不満を抱く騎士たちにとっては　まさに天の声
I am sure they have found that leader in you.
自分たちを導く存在が現れたと感じているに違いありません
大仰だな
You honor me.
On the other hand, this also means that rebellious factions will plot against me.
しかし一方で　反旗を翻す勢力も必ずや現れる
For that, I will require your assistance.
そのために　やってもらいたいことがある
You wish to make an example, then?
力を見せつけろ　ということでしょうか
No, dealing with them individually will only bog us down.
いや　いちいちそういう者たちにかかずらってもきりがない
I need you to root out the most dangerous elements.
まず　危険分子を洗い出せ
We can let the appropriate authorities handle it from there.
そのあとはしかるべき部署にでも任せればいい
はあ
My lord?
Princess Asseylum's name alone should be enough.
アセイラム姫の名があれば動かせる
It should not prove too difficult to strip them of their knighthoods with some flimsy accusation.
適当な罪状で　騎士という身分を剥奪させることも容易のはず
You disapprove?
軽蔑するか　姑息すぎると
Too dirty a trick?
No, my lord. Quite the opposite.
いえ　その逆でございます
It's only natural that you should stop at nothing to achieve your goal.
目的のためには手段を選ばぬことは当然
あの宣言以降　何か…　その…
Since the announcement, I...
If I may be so bold, you seem to have prepared for the worst.
失礼ながら　腹をくくられたような
I wanted to be with Her Highness.
姫様に近づきたいと願っていました
I wanted to be worthy of her.
姫様に相応しくありたいと願っていました
I wanted to devote what power I had to her.
そして　姫様のために力を持ちたいと
But...
だけど…
もうこの手に掴めるものが　力以外にないのなら…
If power is the only thing left that I can aspire to now...
Is that you, Harklight? Come in.
ハークライトか　入れ
ス…スレイン様
Sir Slaine...
エデルリッゾさん
Eddelrittuo?
現状の貴艦の行動に関しては　十分満足している
We are quite satisfied with your ship's operations.
We would like you to continue providing support as a special forces unit.
しばらくこのまま遊撃隊として　各隊の支援に務めてもらいたい
I have no objections.
そのことに異存はありません
But what of Princess Asseylum's announcement?
ただ　アセイラム姫の宣言のことですが…
A new kingdom on Earth?
地球圏に新王朝を築くというあれか
Big words to inspire the knights, but there is nothing more to it.
単に火星騎士たちを鼓舞するための大風呂敷　そういう類だろう
Perhaps.
そうかもしれません
However, we should consider the possibility that this might usher in a new offensive.
ただ　敵の攻撃が次のステージに移るという可能性も考慮には入れるべきかと
Are you implying that we're not doing all we can already?
こちらが黙って手を拱いている
そう言いたいのかな　君は
いえ　そのようなつもりは
No, sir. Not at all.
We are preparing new operations with our principal forces.
新たな作戦に関しては現在　主要な部隊と調整を行っているところだ
Once they are in position, we will contact you.
それが決定したところで　追って君たちにも連絡が行く
We understand you may prefer a more conventional post,
遊撃隊という立場に不満を抱いてるのかもしれんが
but we can never fully trust a ship that runs on the enemy's power source.
敵の力で動いているような船をどこまで信じて良いか
That's simply how it is.
ありていに言えばそういうことだ
I'm surprised you didn't lash out at them.
よく声をあげずに我慢できましたね
あげてほしかったですか
Should I have?
I'm only here as your escort.
護衛としてついてきてるだけですからね
And I'm not as impulsive as you seem to think.
さすがにそこまで世間知らずじゃない
They don't understand.
彼らは　分かっていません
They have no vision,
向こうに見る目がないだけでしょう
やれるだけのことはやっている
but they're doing what they can.
I'm not talking about the Deucalion's assignment specifically.
いえ　デューカリオンの扱いに不満を言いたいわけではありません
They're just way too complacent.
ただ　舐めている…
About us, you mean?
我々を？
火星を
About Mars.
The moment the war turns a little bit in our favor,
少し戦況が好転しているからといって
徒らに読み誤ったりしていないか
they start acting as though we can't lose.
それが恐ろしい
It's seriously worrying.
I will drain the medical fluid
and transport Her Highness to my castle.
治療液を抜いて　アセイラム姫を僕の城に運びます
Tell no one of this.
このことは内密に
Not even Princess Lemrina.
もちろん　レムリナ姫にも
でも　なぜ…
But why—
Do as I say!
なぜでもだ
I'm sorry.
すみません　怯えさせるつもりは…
I didn't mean to startle you.
No visitors?!
面会謝絶？
Has her condition declined that much?
そこまで悪いのですか　お姉様の状態が
It was something of a miracle
that she held on as long as she has.
ここまで　よくぞ持ちこたえたと言うべきかもしれません
How much longer does she have?
Until later today? Tomorrow?
今日明日の話ということになるのでしょうか
それはまだ分からないそうです
We don't know.
あるいは　このままの状態で長引く可能性も
It's equally possible that she may
remain in this condition indefinitely.
そうですか
I see.
Know that I sympathize fully.
お気持ちお察しいたします
You may have mixed feelings,
but she is, after all, your only sister.
複雑な思いもおありでしょうが
やはり　唯一血を分けたご兄弟
You're the one who's truly in pain, aren't you,
本当に悲しいのは　あなたでしょう
スレイン
Slaine?
失礼します
Please excuse me.
Slaine.
スレイン
It's okay, Slaine.
許します　スレイン
今日は　私の前で涙を見せても
You don't have to hold yourself back in my presence.
あの人のために泣いてあげても
You can cry for her if you need to.
もう　私は…
Because I...
am already yours.
あなたのものだから
Could that have triggered it?
あれが　きっかけ
No...
そんな…　まさか
It couldn't be.
I always admired you.
あなたに憧れていた 自分にないものをすべて持っていて
You had all that I did not.
And so I hated you.
だから　憎かった
Don't worry, Sister.
でも心配しないで　お姉様
I will be there for Slaine in your stead.
これからは　本当に私があなたの代わり
これからは　私がスレインの支えになるの
I will support him when you cannot.
どうして
Why?
ええ　どうなの　それ
Huh? What's that about?
Did she get left behind?
置いていかれちゃったってこと？
She was all, "The captain entrusted me with the ship in her absence,"
「私を信頼して留守を任せてくれたんです」
なんて言ってるけど　絶対心穏やかじゃないよ　不見咲中佐
but I seriously doubt Mizusaki's taking it that well on the inside.
I mean, the captain's all alone with Lieutenant Marito now.
よりによって鞠戸大尉でしょう　同伴の相手
Alone? He's her guard.
同伴って　護衛だろう
What's this about Lieutenant Marito?
鞠戸大尉がどうかした？
O-Oh, um...
あっ　いえ　あの…
艦長と一緒に会議に出てるみたいで　なんか大変だなって
Just that he had to go with the captain to that meeting.
Sounds serious.
I see.
そう
火星の宣言もあったし　確かにいろいろ変わってきてるね　状況が
After that Martian proclamation,
our situation's definitely been changing.
I can't believe the princess is getting married.
あの姫様が結婚なんてな
That's what you're focusing on?
そこ　興味？
Hey, come on.
いや　だけどさ
You think she might have changed her mind because of that guy?
姫様が心変わりしたのも
そういう相手がいたからだって考えられないか
Maybe he sweet-talked her,
and one thing led to another, and...
その相手に唆されたとか
I'll shut up.
すみません
Still, we can't be entirely sure that was the Princess Asseylum we knew, right?
でも　あのアセイラム姫が
本当に私たちと一緒にいた姫様かどうかってこと
それもまだ分からないんですよね
Honestly, I don't know.
正直何とも言えないな
Inaho seems convinced she's a fake,
but there's no telling how perceptive he really is.
伊奈帆君は偽物だと主張しているみたいだけど
彼でさえ　どこまで見えているのか
食事はしたの？
Did you eat yet?
もう少し　きりのいいところまで
I will soon. Let me just wrap this up.
変わらないな　小さい頃から
You've been like this ever since you were a kid.
When you get engrossed, nothing else matters.
夢中になるとそればっかり
Here.
はい
ありがとう　ユキ姉
Thanks, Yuki.
聞いたよね　あのアセイラム姫の…
You've heard, right? About Asseylum's, uh...
Yeah.
あの宣言　なお君の言ってたことを証明してるみたいに思えた
That proclamation seemed to confirm everything you've been saying.
何だか話が都合よく動きすぎてるし
Everything's just too neatly wrapped up.
Would the real Asseylum even want to create a kingdom on Earth, you know?
本当にアセイラム姫が本物なら
地球圏に王国なんて話　考えるかなって
スレイン・トロイヤード
Slaine Troyard.
The piece of shit that shot my dear little brother?
私の可愛い弟を撃ったクズ野郎ね
ありがとう　でも言葉遣いが汚いよ　ユキ姉
I appreciate the sentiment, Yuki,
but that language doesn't suit you.
It doesn't matter if she's real or not.
もう　今の彼女が本物かどうかなんて関係ない
誰も耳を貸そうとはしないだろうな
I doubt anyone would listen to her.
Not even if she tried for peace between Earth and Mars again.
彼女がもう一度　地球と火星を平和に導こうとしても
地球への攻撃の件ですが　支障がなければ準備を開始させますが
With your permission, I'd like to begin preparing for the attack on Earth.
スレイン様
Sir Slaine?
I heard you.
聞いている
予定通りことを運べ
Proceed as planned.
Of course.
はい
姫殿下はまだ…
Her Highness has yet to—
じき目覚める　必ず
She'll wake up soon. I know it.
I certainly hope so, sir.
待ち遠しゅうございますね　その時が
ああ　だが　恐ろしくもある
So do I.
But at the same time, I'm afraid.
Sir?
Nothing.
いや
Has there been any change?
姫様にお変わりは？
No. They believe she may remain in this condition for some time.
はい　しばらくはこの状態が続くのではないかと
We can wait.
いくらでも待ちます
It's all we do.
待つことには慣れています
さぞや驚かれるでしょうね
I bet she'll be surprised to find out
how much has changed.
お目覚めになられたら　何もかも変わっていて
And me?
僕も…
僕も　変わって見えるでしょうか
Will I have changed in her eyes?
それは　随分ご立派になられただろうと　きっと
I'm sure she'll think you've grown into a fine man.
I'll come again.
また来ます
スレイン様
Sir Slaine!
...rittuo.
リッゾ…
Eddelrittuo.
エデルリッゾ
Your Highness...
姫様
I...
私…
Your Highness!
姫様　姫様が　お目覚めに
You're awake!
Your Highness, it's me!
姫様　僕です　スレインです
Slaine!
Do you remember?
分かりますか
スレイン　スレイン・トロイヤードです
It's Slaine!
Slaine Troyard!
Slaine Troyard...
スレイン・トロイヤードです
Your Highness...
姫様
Slaine...
レイン
スレイン
Slaine...
Your Highness!
姫様
I've been waiting so long
to hear you say my name again!
ずっと　ずっとお待ちしていました
その名を　再びお呼び頂けることを
まずは無事で何よりだった　マズゥールカ卿
Allow me to say that I am pleased to see you safe, Count Mazuurek.
Thank you for your concern, Count Barouhcruz.
ご心配をおかけいたしました　バルークルス卿
So, what will you do next?
時に　この先は
まだ　何も
I do not know.
カタフラクトも失ってしまいました
I have lost my Cataphract, too.
If you wish to join Count Troyard,
I can approach him on your behalf.
トロイヤード卿につく気があれば　間を取り持っても構わんぞ
マリルシャン卿の件　伺いました
I heard about Count Marylcian.
さぞ無念であっただろうと
A regrettable outcome.
No, both sides fought fairly, and that was the outcome.
何　互いに正々堂々戦った末の結果だ
恨みを抱く話ではない
Resentment would be a waste of time and energy.
バルークルス卿　トロイヤードは危険です
Count Barouhcruz, Troyard is dangerous.
マリルシャン卿の命ばかりではなく
Not only did he kill Count Marylcian,
but some also say he killed Count Saazba—
あやつは　ザーツバルム卿を殺めた疑いさえかけ…
And who...
そのようなこと　だれが？
told you that?
Well...
いえ　しかし…
But, sir...
口を慎め
Mind yourself.
根も葉もない流言に惑わされてどうする
We must not let ourselves be misled by unfounded rumors.
アセイラム姫殿下の宣言　貴公も聞いたであろう
You heard Princess Asseylum's proclamation, I take it?
No one in existence can halt
Count Troyard's momentum.
今やトロイヤード卿の勢いを止められる者はいない
アルドノアの起動権までも手中に収めたとあってはな
He holds all the cards,
including Aldnoah activation.
オリンポスの砂嵐には抗うなかれだ
As they say, "fight not an Olympus sandstorm."
まだ貴公も一花咲かす気があるなら
If you wish to regain your status,
I would think your choice is clear.
選択を間違えぬことだな
バルークルス卿は全面的に協力を約束されております
Count Barouhcruz has promised his full support.
Counts Sebring and Raffia remain tight-lipped,
but do not appear to reject the new kingdom.
ゼブリン卿　ラフィア卿も
これまで旗幟を鮮明に示しておりませんでしたが
新王国を肯定する立場に立たれたようです
基地内の士気も高まっています
Base morale is rising as well.
抵抗する懸念がありそうな騎士たちのリストも
And I have nearly finished going through the list of knights that would likely pose a threat.
ほぼ洗い出しが終わりました
You have the option to take
forceful measures if need be.
いつでも強制的な措置を行うことが可能です
スレイン様
Sir Slaine?
どうかなされましたか
Is something amiss?
失礼ながら　アセイラム姫殿下のご快癒と関係が？
Forgive the question, but is
Princess Asseylum's recovery on your mind?
暇をですか　エデルリッゾに？
You want to give Eddelrittuo some time off?
はい
Yes.
しばしの間で構いません
Even a little is fine.
アセイラム姫の急変に彼女も痛く衝撃をうけておりまして
I'm sure that Princess Asseylum's
sudden turn came as a shock to her.
It must have, yes.
無理もありませんね
あなたの方こそいかがです　スレイン
But how are you, Slaine?
心配していました
I've been worried.
お気遣い感謝いたします
You are too kind.
You are the only one I can rely on now.
もう僕には姫様の他に頼れるお方はおりません
ヴァースをこの手に収めて見せます
I will make Vers mine.
姫殿下のおん為に
For Her Highness.
テイルズ小隊　オルロフ小隊　現在敵揚陸城に向け　進軍中
Dales Platoon and Orlov Platoon are
heading to the enemy Landing Castle.
Clydesdale and Mustang platoons,
watch for enemy Cataphracts.
クライスデール　マスタング
両遊撃隊は　敵カタフラクトに備え
Upon sighting, launch, intercept, and eliminate.
発見した際は速やかに攻撃態勢を確立
撃破せよ
They're lovely.
きれい
Indeed.
はい　スレイン様が姫様のためにと　この庭園を
Sir Slaine had this garden created for Your Highness.
そうですか
Really?
It's like a scene from Earth.
地球の景色ですね
It is!
はい
思い出してきましたか　地球のことを
Are you starting to remember?
I was...
鳥を…
鳥を見ました　あの方と
I was watching birds with that boy.
界塚伊奈帆　ですか
Kaizuka Inaho?
界塚…
Kaizuka...
どうかしましたか
What's the matter?
N-Nothing!
いえ
My, aren't those flowers pretty?
き…きれいですね　あの花も
こちらはテイルズ小隊　現在オルロフ小隊とともに
This is Dales Platoon.
En route to enemy Landing Castle with Orlov Platoon.
敵揚陸城に接近中
クライスデール小隊は？
Clydesdale Platoon, status?
The arrowheads carry highly
explosive payloads! Stay sharp!
矢じりに強力な炸薬弾がついている　気をつけろ
この…
Damn you!
Don't waste your ammunition!
無駄弾を撃つな
敵は姿を隠している上に　動きが早い
Not only is the enemy cloaked, it moves too fast!
It seems to be using a bow, which means...
弓を使ってるようだが　恐らく…
Right.
ええ　銃撃ではマズルフラッシュで位置を特定しやすい
A gun would be easy to spot via the muzzle flash.
They must be avoiding that.
それを避けるためでしょう
Optical camouflage?
光学迷彩？
Invisibility technology?
透明化のテクノロジー
ベースは恐らく
It's most likely based on that.
But it's even more impressive.
ただ　非常に巧妙だ
It's not showing up via thermography, and there's no shadow.
サーモグラフィにも反応しないし　影も落とさない
However...
でも…
間違いなく　存在している
It's real, all right.
ええ
Right.
これを私に？
This is for me?
Customize it however you see fit.
好きにカスタマイズすればいい
I've already cleared your title and
activation factor with Princess Lemrina.
爵位とアルドノア起動権についても
レムリナ姫に話は通している
Sir Slaine...
スレイン様
The first shot has been fired.
既に矢は放たれた　もう後戻りはできない
We are at war now.
はい
Yes, sir.
ゼブリン卿　ラフィア卿　オルガ卿に告げよ
Tell Count Sebring, Count Raffia, and Count Orga
忠誠の証を示せと
to swear their loyalty.
煙幕弾　装填完了
Smoke grenades armed!
Locked and loaded.
こっちもオーケー
ファイア
Fire!
That's right. It's really there.
そう　間違いなく存在している
そして　存在する限り
And if it's really there...
it will have an effect on the air currents.
大気の流れに影響は及ぶ
Target spotted.
ターゲット捕捉
よし　攻撃開始
Right!
Let's get the bastard!
大尉
Lieutenant!
どうした
What is it?
Enemy at three o'clock!
三時の方向　敵が…
Huh?
New enemy rushing straight at us!
正面より　新たな敵接近
A coordinated effort, huh?
連携して戦おうってか
Incoming, up above!
上からも　来ます
A Landing Castle...
揚陸城
全機　衝撃に備えろ
All units, brace for impact!
Multiple Landing Castles.
複数の揚陸城
Multiple Cataphracts.
複数のカタフラクトが　同時に…
All at once.
It's begun.
動き出したんだ　あいつが…
He's made his move.
そう　今更迷うことはない
Right. It's too late for doubts now.
もはや戻れぬところまできてしまったのだ　僕は…
I've come too far to turn back.
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
日听:ikoko&Archer  翻译:mam&郝郝
校对:安少&zwx  时间轴:Foyzi  压制:河蟹
bokutachi wa samayoeru mirai
We are a future of dubious likelihood
僕たちは　彷徨える未来
窮屈な空に　ヒカリを探している
kyuukutsu na sora ni
We look to the oppressive sky
hikari wo sagashiteiru
in search of light
furueru te wa muryoku de
Our trembling hands are powerless
震える手は無力で
sakebi wa mata tookute
Our screams reach no one
叫びはまだ遠くて
dakedo tobu koto wo
But we will never be afraid
たけど飛ぶことを恐れてはいられない
osorete wa irarenai
of flying
永遠じゃなくても　完璧じゃなくても
eien ja nakutemo
We don't need eternity
kanpeki ja nakutemo
We don't need perfection
senaka-awase no sekai wo
We live in two related
背中合わせの世界を　真っ直ぐ生きてゆく
massugu ikiteyuku
but wildly different worlds
nando kizu tsuitemo
No matter the wounds we receive
何度傷ついても　何度間違えても
nando machigaetemo
and the mistakes we make,
unmei sae tobikoete yukou
we will overcome fate
運命さえ飛び越えていこう
kono sora no hate made
Until the skies above us end
この宙の果てまで
hajimari wo shinjite
we will believe in the genesis of a better life
創造を信じて